# Roo Williams

150 Dekalb Ave Ground Floor Brooklyn 11217

347-322-8679 roo@roowilliams.com roowilliams.com @roowilliams

### **Profile**

Hello! I am a Design Technologist with a penchant for problem solving and a passion for making products and experiences enabled by the intersection of our physical and digital worlds. Happy, T-shaped person and proud owner of a 7lb miniature pinscher named Betty.

## Experience

#### Senior Creative Technologist - Anomaly, New York City

09/2015 - 09/2017

Championing advertising that is useful rather than distracting.

Created a collection of industry-wide projects as a way to evangelize and develop my own critique of this concept: <a href="https://brandedutility.tumblr.com">https://brandedutility.tumblr.com</a>

Building prototypes to test ideas before committing to a production partner. Serving as an in-house tech-lead, consulting with producers.

Building production level websites.

Facilitator of maker culture within the organization with initiatives like Anomaly SkillShare <a href="http://anomalyskillshare.tumblr.com">http://anomalyskillshare.tumblr.com</a> and teaching people to use digital fabrication tools.

#### Labs Tech Lead - TMW Unlimited, London

07/2014 - 07/2015

Using emerging technologies to concept and build products that bring technical innovation to life at TMW. Managing build teams and using product design skills for physical builds. Project themes include connected objects, contextual/physical computing.

#### Product Designer - TMW Agency, London

07/2012 - 07/2014

Exploring the boundaries between digital and physical. Working with the Director of Innovation, Technical and Creative Directors to develop creative and technically angled solutions for clients and future business.

#### Nike iD Design Consultant - Niketown, London

11/2010 - 01/2012

Duties involve premium customer service, tailored storytelling alongside footwear customizations and telling brand stories.

#### **Graphic Designer - Brand42, London**

2002 - 2012

Worked on UI design for a James Bond, Skyfall campaign for VisitBritain.

#### Prop Designer/Maker, Adam Howe for Dr. Martens

05/2010

Hired by Adam Howe (I-D magazine stylist) to design and make props for use in a Dr. Martens promo video shot by Klaus Thymann in Denmark.

### Product Design Assistant - Adapt-React, Russell Square, London

07/2009 - 10/2009

Paid summer internship helping to develop various products including a notebook case, fabric vase, coat rack and indoor sundial. Duties included creating drawings for laser cutting, getting quotes from suppliers and manufacturers, product development, sketch modelling and packaging design.

#### **Graphic Designer - CC Sports, Bargoed, South Wales**

09/2005 - 08/2008

In-house graphic designer for a printwear and promotion company. Duties involved print design for team wear, design and production of promo material, sporting awards, signage and developing a web presence. Other duties involved implementation, maintenance and administration of the companies IT system.

### Education

BA Product Design - Central Saint Martins, London Student representative, selected to exhibit at New Designers Showcase 2012 2009 - 2012

Foundation studies in Art and Design / **Merit** - Central Saint Martins, London 2009

### Skills

Natural collaborator, get-stuck-in attitude, ability to lead or assist Art direction and graphic design

Research and analysis methods

Design thinking: iterative design, human centered design

UX: personas, journeys, flows, wireframes

Communication: client presentation & pitch skills, ability to clearly discuss and explain solutions with both technical and non-technical team members, documentation of projects, writing, sketching to communicate

Digital prototyping: JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, Experience with React/Vue, React Native Physical prototyping: 3D modelling, 3D printing, laser cutting, workshop skills

Physical computing: Arduino, Raspberry Pi, Electronics